In the previous video, we talked about evaluation metrics.
在之前的视频中 我们讨论了评价指标
(字幕修改合并：中国海洋大学 黄海广
haiguang2000@qq.com )
In this video, I'd like
在这个视频中
to switch tracks a bit and
我要稍微转换一下
touch on another important aspect of
讨论一下机器学习系统设计中
machine learning system design,
另一个重要的方面
which will often come up, which
这往往涉及到
is the issue of how much
用来训练的数据
data to train on.
有多少
Now, in some earlier videos, I
在之前的一些视频中
had cautioned against blindly
我曾告诫大家不要盲目地开始
going out and just spending
而是花大量的时间
lots of time collecting lots of
来收集大量的数据
data, because it's only
因为数据
sometimes that that would actually help.
有时是唯一能实际起到作用的
But it turns out that under
但事实证明
certain conditions, and I
在一定条件下
will say in this video what those
我会在这个视频里讲到
conditions are, getting a
这些条件是什么
lot of data and training on
在这些条件下 得到大量的数据并在
a certain type of learning
某种类型的学习算法中进行训练
algorithm, can be a
可以是一种
very effective way to get
有效的方法来获得
a learning algorithm to do very good performance.
一个具有良好性能的学习算法
And this arises often enough
而这种情况往往出现在
that if those conditions hold true
这些条件对于你的问题
for your problem and if
都成立 并且
you're able to get a lot
你能够得到大量数据的
of data, this could be
情况下 这可以是
a very good way to get
一个很好的方式来获得
a very high performance learning algorithm.
非常高性能的学习算法
So in this video, let's
因此 在这段视频中
talk more about that.
让我们一起讨论一下这个问题
Let me start with a story.
我先讲一个故事
Many, many years ago, two researchers
很多很多年前 我认识的两位研究人员
that I know, Michelle Banko and
Michele Banko 和
Eric Broule ran the following fascinating study.
Eric Brill 进行了一项有趣的研究
They were interested in studying the
他们感兴趣的是研究
effect of using different learning
使用不同的学习算法的效果
algorithms versus trying them
与将这些效果
out on different training set sciences,
使用到不同训练数据集上 两者的比较
they were considering the problem
他们当时考虑这样一个问题
of classifying between confusable words,
如何在易混淆的词之间进行分类
so for example, in the sentence:
比如 在这样的句子中：
for breakfast I ate, should it be to, two or too?
早餐我吃了__个鸡蛋 (to,two too 与 then,than 是两组混淆词)
Well, for this example,
在这个例子中
for breakfast I ate two, 2 eggs.
早餐我吃了2个鸡蛋
So, this is one example
这是一个
of a set of confusable words and that's a different set.
易混淆的单词的例子 而这是另外一组情况
So they took machine learning
于是他们把诸如这样的机器学习问题
problems like these, sort of supervised learning
当做一类监督学习问题
problems to try to categorize
并尝试将其分类
what is the appropriate word to
什么样的词
go into a certain position
在一个英文句子特定的位置
in an English sentence.
才是合适的
They took a few different learning
他们用了几种不同的学习算法
algorithms which were, you know,
这些算法都是
sort of considered state of
在他们2001年进行研究的时候
the art back in the day,
都已经
when they ran the study in
被公认是比较领先的
2001, so they took a
因此他们使用了一个方差
variance, roughly a variance
用于逻辑回归上的一个方差
on logistic regression called the Perceptron.
被称作“感知器” (perceptron)
They also took some of
他们也采取了一些
their algorithms that were fairly
比较公正的算法
out back then but somewhat less
但是现在比较少用了
used now so when the
因此当
algorithm also very similar
这样一个类似于
to which is a regression
回归问题
but different in some ways, much
但在一些方法上又有所不同
used somewhat less, used
过去用得比较多
not too much right now
但现在用得不太多
took what's called a memory based
一种基于内存的学习算法
learning algorithm again used somewhat less now.
现在也用得比较少了
But I'll talk a little bit about that later.
但是我稍后会讨论一点
And they used a naive based
而且他们用了一个朴素算法
algorithm, which is something they'll
这个我们将在
actually talk about in this course.
这门课程中讨论到
The exact algorithms of these details aren't important.
这些具体算法的细节不那么重要
Think of this as, you know, just picking
想象一下
four different classification algorithms and really the exact algorithms aren't important.
仅仅选取四种分类算法 且这些具体算法并不重要
But what they did was they
他们所做的就是
varied the training set size
改变了训练数据集的大小
and tried out these learning
并尝将这些学习
algorithms on the range of
算法用于不同大小的
training set sizes and that's the result they got.
训练数据集中 这就是他们得到的结果
And the trends are very
这些趋势非常明显
clear right first most of
首先大部分
these outer rooms give remarkably similar performance.
外部空间都具有相似的性能
And second, as the training
其次 随着训练
set size increases, on the
数据集的增大
horizontal axis is the
在横轴上代表
training set size in millions
数以百万计的训练集大小
go from you know a
从成百上千到
hundred thousand up to a
成千上万
thousand million that is a
这是一个
billion training examples. The
十亿大小训练集的例子
performance of the algorithms
这些算法的性能
all pretty much monotonically increase
也都对应地增强了
and the fact that if
事实上 如果
you pick any algorithm may be
你选择任意一个算法 可能是
pick a "inferior algorithm" but
选择了一个"劣质的"算法
if you give that "inferior
如果你给这个
algorithm" more data, then from
劣质算法更多的数据 那么
these examples, it looks like
从这些列子中看起来的话 它看上去
it will most likely beat even a "superior algorithm".
很有可能会其他算法更好 甚至会比"优质算法"更好
So since this original study
由于这项原始的研究
which is very influential, there's been
非常具有影响力 因此已经有
a range of many different
一系列许多不同的
studies showing similar results
研究显示了类似的结果
that show that many different learning
这些结果表明 许多不同的学习
algorithms you know tend
算法有时倾向于
to, can sometimes, depending on
依赖一些细节
details, can give pretty similar ranges
并表现出相当相似
of performance, but what can
的性能 但是真正能提高性能的
really drive performance is you can give the algorithm a ton of training data.
是你能够给予一个算法大量的训练数据
And this is, results like these
像这样的结果
has led to a saying in
引起了一种
machine learning that often in
在机器学习中
machine learning it's not
的常用说法：
who has the best algorithm that
并不是拥有最好算法的人能成功
wins, it's who has the
而是拥有最多数据
most data So when is this
的人能成功 那么
true and when is this not true?
这种情况什么时候是真 什么时候是假呢？
Because we have a learning
因为我们有一个学习算法
algorithm for which this is
这种算法在这种情况下是真的
true then getting a
那么得到大量
lot of data is often
的数据通常是
maybe the best way to ensure
保证我们
that we have an algorithm with
具有一个高性能算法
very high performance rather than
的最佳方式 而不是
you know, debating worrying about exactly which of these items to use.
去争辩使用什么样的算法
Let's try to lay out a
假如有这样一些假设
set of assumptions under which having
在这些假设下有
a massive training set we think will be able to help.
大量我们认为有用的训练集
Let's assume that in our
我们假设在我们的
machine learning problem, the features
机器学习问题中 特征值
x have sufficient information with which
x包含了足够的信息
we can use to predict y accurately.
这些信息可以帮助我们用来准确地预测 y
For example, if we take
例如 如果我们采用了
the confusable words all of them that we had on the previous slide.
我们前一张幻灯片里的所有容易混淆的词
Let's say that it features x
假如说它能够描述 x
capture what are the surrounding
捕捉到需要填写
words around the blank that we're trying to fill in.
的周围空白的词语
So the features capture then we
那么特征捕捉到之后
want to have, sometimes for breakfast I have black eggs.
我们就希望有 有些时候是“早饭我吃了__鸡蛋”
Then yeah that is pretty
那么这就有
much information to tell me
大量的信息来告诉我
that the word I want
中间我需要填的
in the middle is TWO and that
词是“两个” (two)
is not word TO and its not the word TOO. So
而不是单词 to 或 too
the features capture, you know, one
因此特征捕捉
of these surrounding words then that
哪怕是周围词语中的一个词
gives me enough information to pretty
就能够给我足够的信息来
unambiguously decide what is
明确
the label y or in
标签 y 是什么
other words what is the word
换句话说
that I should be using to fill
从这三组易混淆的词中
in that blank out of
我应该选什么
this set of three confusable words.
词来填空
So that's an example what
这就是一个例子
the future ex has sufficient information
特征值 x 有充足的信息
for specific y. For
来确定 y
a counter example.
举一个反例
Consider a problem of predicting
设想一个
the price of a house from
房子价格的问题
only the size of the
房子只有大小信息
house and from no other
没有其他特征
features. So
那么
if you imagine I tell you
如果我告诉你
that a house is, you
这个房子有
know, 500 square feet but I don't give you any other features.
500平方英尺 但是我没有告诉你其他的特征信息
I don't tell you that the
我也不告诉你这个
house is in an expensive part of the city.
房子位于这个城市房价比较昂贵的区域
Or if I don't tell you that
如果我也不告诉你
the house, the number of
这所房子的
rooms in the house, or how
房间数量 或者
nicely furnished the house
它里面陈设了多漂亮的家具
is, or whether the house is new or old.
或这个房子是新的还是旧的
If I don't tell you anything other
我不告诉你其他任何信息
than that this is a
除了这个房子
500 square foot house, well there's
有500平方英尺以外
so many other factors that would
然而除此之外还有许多其他因素
affect the price of a
会影响房子
house other than just the size
的价格 不仅仅是房子的大小
of a house that if all
如果所有
you know is the size, it's actually
你所知道的只有房子的尺寸 那么事实上
very difficult to predict the price accurately.
是很难准确预测它的价格的
So that would be a counter
这是这对于这个假设
example to this assumption
的一个反例
that the features have sufficient information
假设是特征能够提供足够的信息
to predict the price to the desired level of accuracy.
来在需要的水平上预测出价格
The way I think about testing
我想检测这样一个
this assumption, one way I
假设的方式是
often think about it is, how often I ask myself.
去思考它 "多久一次？" 我这样问自己
Given the input features x,
给定一个输入特征向量 x
given the features, given the
给定这些特征值
same information available as well as learning algorithm.
也给定了相同的可用的信息和学习算法
If we were to go to human expert in this domain.
如果我们去人类专家这个领域
Can a human experts actually or
一个人类学家能够
can human expert confidently predict
准确或自信的预测出
the value of y. For this
y值吗？
first example if we go
第一个例子 如果我们去
to, you know an expert human English speaker.
找你认识的一个人类专家 说英语的
You go to someone that
你找到了一个
speaks English well, right, then
英语说得很好的人 好 那么
a human expert in English
一个说英语的人类学家
just read most people like
刚好理解大部分像
you and me will probably we
你和我这样的人 可能会
would probably be able to
我们就可能能够
predict what word should go in
预测出在这种情况下
here, to a good English
该使用什么样的语言 对于一个英语说得
speaker can predict this well,
好的人来说 可以预测得很好
and so this gives me confidence
因此这就给了我信心
that x allows us to predict
x能够让我们准确
y accurately, but in contrast
地预测y 但是与此相反
if we go to an expert in human prices.
如果我们去找一个价格上的专家
Like maybe an expert realtor, right, someone
如 可能是一个房地产经纪人专家
who sells houses for a living.
以买房子为生的人
If I just tell them the
如果我只是告诉他们
size of a house and I
一个房子的大小
tell them what the price
并告诉他们房子的价格
is well even an expert
那么即使是房价评估或售房
in pricing or selling
方面的专家
houses wouldn't be able
他也不能
to tell me and so this is fine that
告诉我（房子的预测价格）
for the housing price example knowing
所以在房子价格的例子中
only the size doesn't give
只知道房子的大小并不能
me enough information to predict
给我足够的信息来预测
the price of the house.
房子的价格
So, let's say, this assumption holds.
如果这个假设是成立的
Let's see then, when having
那么让我们来看一看 当有
a lot of data could help.
大量的数据时是有帮助的
Suppose the features have enough
假设特征值有
information to predict the
足够的信息来预测
value of y.
y值
And let's suppose we use a
假设我们使用一种
learning algorithm with a
需要大量参数的
large number of parameters so
学习算法
maybe logistic regression or linear
也许是有很多特征值的
regression with a large number of features.
逻辑回归或线性回归
Or one thing that I sometimes
或者我有时做的一件事
do, one thing that I often
我经常做的一件事
do actually is using neural network with many hidden units.
实际上是在利用许多隐藏单元的神经网络
That would be another learning
那又将使另外一个
algorithm with a lot of parameters.
带有很多参数的学习算法了
So these are all powerful learning
这些都是强大的学习
algorithms with a lot of parameters that
算法 它们有很多参数
can fit very complex functions.
这些参数可以拟合非常复杂的函数
So, I'm going to call these, I'm
因此我要调用这些
going to think of these as
我将把这些算法想象成
low-bias algorithms because you
低偏差算法 因为
know we can fit very complex functions
我们能够拟合非常复杂的函数
and because we have
而且因为我们有
a very powerful learning algorithm,
非常强大的学习算法
they can fit very complex functions.
这些学习算法能够拟合非常复杂的函数
Chances are, if we
很有可能 如果我们
run these algorithms on
用这些数据运行
the data sets, it will
这些算法 这种算法
be able to fit the training
很好地拟合训练集
set well, and so
因此
hopefully the training error will be slow.
训练误差就会很低
Now let's say, we use
现在假设我们使用了
a massive, massive training set,
非常非常大的训练集
in that case, if we
在这种情况下 如果我们
have a huge training set, then
有一个庞大的训练集 那么
hopefully even though we have a lot of parameters
尽管我们希望有很多参数
but if the training set is sort of even much
但是如果训练集比
larger than the number of
比参数的数量大一些
Right because we have such a
因为我们有如此
massive training set and by
庞大的训练集
unlikely to overfit what that
并且不太可能过度拟合
means is that the training
也就是说训练
error will hopefully be
误差有希望
close to the test error.
接近测试误差
Finally putting these two
最后把这两个
together that the train
放在一起 训练集
set error is small and
误差很小 而
the test set error is close
测试集误差又接近
to the training error what
训练误差
this two together imply is
这两个就意味着
that hopefully the test set error
测试集的误差
will also be small.
也会很小
Another way to
另一种考虑
think about this is that
这个问题的方式是
in order to have a high
为了有一个高
performance learning algorithm we want
性能的学习算法 我们希望
it not to have high bias and not to have high variance.
它不要有高的偏差和方差
So the bias problem we're going
因此偏差问题 我么将
to address by making sure we
通过确保
have a learning algorithm with many
有一个具有很多
parameters and so that
参数的学习算法来保证 以便
gives us a low bias alorithm
我们能够得到一个较低偏差的算法
and by using a
并且通过用
very large training set, this ensures
非常大的训练集来保证
that we don't have a variance problem here.
我们在此没有方差问题
So hopefully our algorithm will
我们的算法将
have no variance and so
没有方差 并且
is by pulling these two together,
通过将这两个值放在一起
that we end up with a low
我们最终可以得到一个低
bias and a low variance
误差和低方差
learning algorithm and this
的学习算法 这
allows us to do well
使得我们能够
on the test set.
很好地测试测试数据集
And fundamentally it's a key ingredients
从根本上来说 这是一个关键
of assuming that the features
的假设：特征值
have enough information and we
有足够的信息量 且我们
have a rich class of functions
有一类很好的函数
that's why it guarantees low bias,
这是为什么能保证低误差的关键所在
and then it having a massive
它有大量的
training set that that's what guarantees more variance.
训练数据集 这能保证得到更多的方差值
So this gives us a
因此这给我们提出了
set of conditions rather hopefully
一些可能的条件
some understanding of what's the
一些对于
sort of problem where if
问题的认识 如果
you have a lot of data
你有大量的数据
and you train a learning
而且你训练了一种
algorithm with lot of parameters, that might
带有很多参数的学习算法 那么这将
be a good way to give
会是一个很好的方式来提供
a high performance learning algorithm
一个高性能的学习算法
and really, I think the key test that
我觉得关键的测试
I often ask myself are
我常常问自己 是
first, can a human experts
首先 一个人类专家
look at the features x and
看到了特征值x 且
confidently predict the value of
能很有信心的预测出
y. Because that's sort of
y值吗？ 因为这可以
a certification that y
证明y
can be predicted accurately from
可以根据特征值
the features x and second,
x被准确地预测出来 其次
can we actually get a large
我们实际上能得到一组
training set, and train the
庞大的训练集并且在这个
learning algorithm with a lot of
训练集中训练一个有
parameters in the training
很多参数的学习算法吗？
set and if you can't do both
如果你不能做到这两者
then that's more often give
那么这更多时候
you a very kind performance learning algorithm.
你会得到一个性能很好的学习算法